KARABO MALOKA

BUSINESS INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY GRADUATE

Auckland Park, Johannesburg, +27 81 214 7312 | karabomaloka92@gmail.com

PROFILE SUMMARY

As a recent graduate in Business Information Technology from the University of Johannesburg, I've acquired valuable skills and insights in the IT sector. My profound interest in Journalism and Media Studies provides a distinctive lens for optimising the media industry through technology. Alongside my experience in UX Design and Mobile App development, I also excel in coordinating events and have served as an MC for multiple hackathons, showcasing my ability to bring people together and create engaging experiences.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Communication	• • • • •	Business Acumen	$\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet$
Research and Investigation	• • • • •	Collaboration	• • • • •
Networking and Relationship building	••••	Creativity and Innovation	• • • •

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Web Development: HTML, CSS, React Native, Web Design	• • • •	Canva: Posters, Flyers, Reports, ● ● ● ● Presentations and videos.
Figma: Designing Prototypes	••••	Technical Writing: Documentation ● ● ● ●
Multimedia Software: Adobe Photoshop, InDesign, Premiere Pro	• • • •	Copywriting Techniques: social ● ● ● ● media posts, and brand voice

LANGUAGES

English	• • • •	Sesotho	• • • • •
Afrikaans	••••	SeTswana	••••

EDUCATION

Diploma in Business Information Technology 2021 - 2023

University of Johannesburg

Relevant coursework: Web Development, Database Management,

Digital Business Strategy, Business Analytics

Diploma in Journalism and Media Studies 2017 - 2019

Damelin, South Africa

Relevant coursework: Media Production, Media Studies,

Adobe Photoshop and Adobe InDesign

WORK EXPERIENCE

Coordinator and UX Designer

Feb 2023 - current

Technopreneurship Centre, Johannesburg

- Coordinated events, workshops, and training sessions to foster innovation and entrepreneurial skills among participants.
- Led UX design initiatives, creating intuitive and user-friendly interfaces for digital products and platforms.

Intern Image Retoucher

March, 2020 - July, 2020

Silo, Johannesburg

- Collaborated with a team of designers and developers to create usercentered designs
- Utilized design thinking methodologies to create intuitive and engaging user interfaces

Editor (Damelin Vaal Campus) Melin Era Magazine, Vereeniging

Apr 2019 - Oct 2019

- Conducted interviews, wrote articles and created content for print and online publication
- Conducted user research and analyzed data to inform design decisions

HONOURS & AWARDS

- Mobile App Development at BRICS Skills Challenge
- MC for AlMashup Hackathon in partnership with Microsoft and the UJ Women in ICT Webinar
- Student Assistant and Tutor (Development Software 2A & 2B), 2023
- Artificial Intelligence in 4IR certificate
- UJenius club 2022
- EPF Heritage Hackathon Winner 2022
- Career Influencer at PsyCaD (Volunteering)
- First Year Marshal (Volunteering)

PROJECTS

UJ Incident Reporting Platform University of Johannesburg, 2023

Aug 2023 - current

- UJ incident reporting platform is a valuable initiative to address and combat instances of bullying, harassment, rape, and other forms of gender-based violence around and within the university community.
- Led the UX design efforts for the development of the incident reporting platform at UJ
- Successfully delivered a platform that empowers UJ students to report incidents and seek assistance while maintaining their anonymity.

MASS (Master Assessment Scheduling System) University of Johannesburg, 2023

Year long project

- This is a web based platform to simplify the process of scheduling student module assessments, prevent conflicts, and improve student preparation and performance.
- The MASS platform will be integrated with all active modules in the AIS department at the University of Johannesburg.

Website Development Project Johannesburg, 2023

Present

 Developed a personal portfolio website which demonstrate my understanding of web development languages like HTML, CSS, and web design principles. This portfolio will relate to my interests in Journalism and Technology.

REFERENCES

Dr Stella Byuma

Director: School of Consumer Intelligence and Information Systems (SCiiS) (+27) 11 559 1139/1189 stellab@uj.ac.za

Ronny Mabokela

Head of Technopreneurship Centre (+27) 11 559 2112 rmabokela@uj.ac.za

Bheki Mbatha

Damelin, South Africa (+27) 71 139 3864 bhekimbatha8@gmail.com